<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[PRAXIS]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.png</url><title>PRAXIS</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 09:54:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 09:54:06 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Avatar Zarya: The Dragon Princess]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><img src="\lib\media\avatar-concept.png"><br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="\lib\media\gamelans-album-art.jpg">  #### Suggested Music

**Java** - Gamelans From The Sultans Palace In Jogjakarta

The most common instruments used in Gamelan are metallophones played by mallets and a set of hand-played drums called kendhang which register the beat.

[\[PLAY IN YOUTUBE\]](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PDLDqh0Xpew) 
Java - Gamelans From The Sultans Palace In Jogjakarta
The most common instruments used in Gamelan are metallophones played by mallets and a set of hand-played drums called kendhang which register the beat.
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PDLDqh0Xpew" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PDLDqh0Xpew" target="_blank">[PLAY IN YOUTUBE]</a> <br>Ideas: Distrust of authority, phobia of confined spaces (anxiety), lack of sociability (via seclusion; social anxiety), performance anxiety = &lt;100% success rate -&gt; mastery = &gt;100% speed, hyperawareness: insomnia/hallucinations/dissociation/memory fragmentations, survivors guilt, having not seeing water in ages a sip restores a bit of conscious away from feral animal,<br>
How man reacts to impulse define what type of man he is: like lightning redirecting through the body<br><br>Zarya begins in a combustion bending camp off the record from any government authorities, thus technologically outdated. Owners unknown. The workers appear to be non-benders.<br><br>He finds herself in the Si Wong Desert at night. Grateful and vowing to return, she took the opportunity to run as far as possible, warmed her hands with firebending when needed. <br>Nearly passing out, she uses the last of her energy to stumble to the ragtag shelter on the horizon. The underwater 'breath training' paid off.<br>She fell asleep for what felt like minutes and woke up startled by the sound of a sandstorm approaching. Sandbenders en route to passing right by her in the distance. Desperate for water, she conjures her last bits of chi into shooting a fireball signal into the air above them at a non-threatening angle. She took a minute to take choked breaths and shoot another one. Their apocalyptic echos of sand-sailers slowed and two out of the three changed directions and headed towards her.<br><br><br><br><br><br><br><img src="\lib\media\moveset.jpg"><br><br><img src="\lib\media\graphics-test.png">]]></description><link>documents\avatar-zarya.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Documents/AVATAR ZARYA.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 22:04:41 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\avatar-concept.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\avatar-concept.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>