<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[PRAXIS]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.png</url><title>PRAXIS</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 07:30:58 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 07:29:41 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>(Error) Image Gallery: The folder doesn't exist, or it's empty!]]></description><link>projects\avatar\assets\index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Assets/index.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:49:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jarvis Sato: Mastermind Equalist]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Art by <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="http://www.robotpencil.net/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="http://www.robotpencil.net/" target="_blank">Anthony Jones</a><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="lib\media\jarvis-sato-icon.png">  A spiritual successor to Amon, **Jarvis Sato** masterminds a brand new Equalist movement with his Future Industries CTO money. He obtained a spirit world equivalent of Jennamite which he surgically bound to his chest and it lightly burrowed through his body forming a symbiotic relationship, most of the initial growth surgically removed. As long as his tech keeps it stabilized, his energy-hungry suit can channel it's power. A spiritual successor to Amon, Jarvis Sato masterminds a brand new Equalist movement with his Future Industries CTO money. He obtained a spirit world equivalent of Jennamite which he surgically bound to his chest and it lightly burrowed through his body forming a symbiotic relationship, most of the initial growth surgically removed. As long as his tech keeps it stabilized, his energy-hungry suit can channel it's power. ]]></description><link>projects\avatar\characters\jarvis-sato.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Characters/Jarvis Sato.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:08:44 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\jarvis-sato-icon.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\jarvis-sato-icon.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jin: The Yuyan Combustion-Bender]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="lib\media\yuyan-combustion-icon.png">  **Jin** is a stoic yuyan archer captured for Unanimity who maintains his vow of silence throughout. He begins as a weak victimized character with a starved medium-tall stature during his appearance in Unanimity, no tattoo. He reappears in the future as a full-on Unanimity mercenary who completed his training and is loyal enough to his 'contractors' to one day encounter Shunen again as an opponent until they recognize each other. Jin is a stoic yuyan archer captured for Unanimity who maintains his vow of silence throughout. He begins as a weak victimized character with a starved medium-tall stature during his appearance in Unanimity, no tattoo. He reappears in the future as a full-on Unanimity mercenary who completed his training and is loyal enough to his 'contractors' to one day encounter Shunen again as an opponent until they recognize each other. <br><br>Slim inmates never make it far, due to lack of adequate lung expansion.<br>
They all fell to torturous painful deaths.<br>This former yuyan archer seems unassuming from his starved stature but his final test has arrived, stoic determination unwavering.<br>Zarya's friend, the only source of sympathy in Hell. She's never heard his voice but his kind actions speak volumes.<br>A resourceful master of improvisation and seasoned rogue, San assists Zarya in putting together the contraband required to attempt escaping.<br>He presumably died saving Zarya during the breakout.]]></description><link>projects\avatar\characters\jin.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Characters/Jin.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:08:52 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\yuyan-combustion-icon.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\yuyan-combustion-icon.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kaliph: Royal Mummy-Like Sandbender]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="lib\media\kaliph-icon.png">  **The Kaliph** is teated like a spiritual leader in the Si Wong settlement. His specialty is mudbending which he uses like Kuvira/Dai Lee. He has an unusually large body and a wheezy, harsh voice that he uses very sparingly due to a burn injury on the throat and upper body. Adorned in jewelry and wrapped like a mummy, his status was earned by helping build the settlement from the ground up and resolving conflicts with a heavy hand. He carries a sword and gourd of mud. The Kaliph is teated like a spiritual leader in the Si Wong settlement. His specialty is mudbending which he uses like Kuvira/Dai Lee. He has an unusually large body and a wheezy, harsh voice that he uses very sparingly due to a burn injury on the throat and upper body. Adorned in jewelry and wrapped like a mummy, his status was earned by helping build the settlement from the ground up and resolving conflicts with a heavy hand. He carries a sword and gourd of mud. ]]></description><link>projects\avatar\characters\kaliph.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Characters/Kaliph.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:08:58 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\kaliph-icon.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\kaliph-icon.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mei Lin: Energetic Air Acolyte]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="lib\media\air-acolyte.webp">  **Mei Lin** visited the Western Air Temple just because the Nomad visitors in her town were "so pretty and nice" and though she didn't really take to all the customs (quite materialistic and cares too much about her appearance), she decided to stay and everyone loves her joyous energy tempered with charisma and elegance. She especially enjoys Samaya's company. She is an Earth-born non-bender Air Acolyte who loves yoga and gardening but hates meditating. Mei Lin visited the Western Air Temple just because the Nomad visitors in her town were "so pretty and nice" and though she didn't really take to all the customs (quite materialistic and cares too much about her appearance), she decided to stay and everyone loves her joyous energy tempered with charisma and elegance. She especially enjoys Samaya's company. She is an Earth-born non-bender Air Acolyte who loves yoga and gardening but hates meditating. <br>Mei Lin (美琳) in Chinese combines beauty with elegance]]></description><link>projects\avatar\characters\mei-lin.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Characters/Mei Lin.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:09:04 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\air-acolyte.webp" length="0" type="image/webp"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\air-acolyte.webp&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Red Spirit]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="lib\media\red-spirit.jpg">  Inspired by the Blue Spirit of legend who saved the Air Avatar past, the **Red Spirit** alter ego was born. With her Kusarigama, she can crowd control with intimidation and unpredictability. She can use the chain side as a whip to shatter bones (gunshot sound) or tangle it around sword hilts and legs if a weight or mini-hook is attached. She accrues a Robin Hood-like reputation in her area with a heavy bounty on her head. Inspired by the Blue Spirit of legend who saved the Air Avatar past, the Red Spirit alter ego was born. With her Kusarigama, she can crowd control with intimidation and unpredictability. She can use the chain side as a whip to shatter bones (gunshot sound) or tangle it around sword hilts and legs if a weight or mini-hook is attached. She accrues a Robin Hood-like reputation in her area with a heavy bounty on her head. ]]></description><link>projects\avatar\characters\red-spirit.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Characters/Red Spirit.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:09:11 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\red-spirit.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\red-spirit.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Samaya: Whimsical Air Master]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Artist: @avie_elisabet<br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="lib\media\nymia-icon.png">  **Samaya** is passionate about dancing, arts and cooking great vegetarian food. She is a soft-spoken respectful yet confident and talkative girl with a playful teasing nature who's found peace from within herself and from nature, a stark contrast from MC but he warms up quickly and indulges the banter (she's the big sister he never had). She is often found enjoying views alone while holding various impressive acrobatic poses effortlessly or hanging out with Mei Lin. She obtained her mastery tattoos at 19. Samaya is passionate about dancing, arts and cooking great vegetarian food. She is a soft-spoken respectful yet confident and talkative girl with a playful teasing nature who's found peace from within herself and from nature, a stark contrast from MC but he warms up quickly and indulges the banter (she's the big sister he never had). She is often found enjoying views alone while holding various impressive acrobatic poses effortlessly or hanging out with Mei Lin. She obtained her mastery tattoos at 19. <br>Samaya (དམ་ཚིག) in Tibetan means 'sacred promise'.<br>Also consider Yara (East mountain peak), Zaya (flourishing), Ema (exclamation of joy), Maya (magic/illusion, religious name)<br>Fun fact: she's a far descendant of Ty Lee.]]></description><link>projects\avatar\characters\samaya.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Characters/Samaya.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:09:16 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\nymia-icon.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\nymia-icon.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Shu Ming: Fallen Airbender]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="lib\media\monzart_airbender.jpg">  **Shu Ming** is Shunen's mother. She was incredibly spritually-attuned able to spiritually project and enter the Spirit World (a Spirit Library scholar). That was before Shunen was concieved with a firebending father who left when things went downhill: her bending became weaker, her health/self-love declined and she lost her spiritual abilities. Despite it all, she was always an incredibly loving and caring mother, sister and helper. After Shunen's capture, she fell apart and started using fans to maintain her dying bending. Shu Ming is Shunen's mother. She was incredibly spritually-attuned able to spiritually project and enter the Spirit World (a Spirit Library scholar). That was before Shunen was concieved with a firebending father who left when things went downhill: her bending became weaker, her health/self-love declined and she lost her spiritual abilities. Despite it all, she was always an incredibly loving and caring mother, sister and helper. After Shunen's capture, she fell apart and started using fans to maintain her dying bending. <br>The name comes from the Chinese characters (cultivate, life).]]></description><link>projects\avatar\characters\shu-ming.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Characters/Shu Ming.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:09:22 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\monzart_airbender.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\monzart_airbender.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Shunen: Nomad-raised Combustion-bender]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="lib\media\shunen.jpg">  **Shunen** is a combustion bender who was captured at a young age from his Air Nomad mother and survived the Unanimity trials until he escaped at 16.  He regularly risked exploring the facility, against the threat of solitary confinement, electrocution and/or "reprogramming." He is nimble, empathetic, resilient and hyper-vigilant. He used his prodigious firebending, with an affinity for speed, to defend helpless inmates. Shunen is a combustion bender who was captured at a young age from his Air Nomad mother and survived the Unanimity trials until he escaped at 16.  He regularly risked exploring the facility, against the threat of solitary confinement, electrocution and/or "reprogramming." He is nimble, empathetic, resilient and hyper-vigilant. He used his prodigious firebending, with an affinity for speed, to defend helpless inmates. <br>The name comes from the Chinese characters 樹嫩 (cultivate, delicate). He looks just like his father but has his mother's eyes.]]></description><link>projects\avatar\characters\shunen.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Characters/Shunen.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:09:28 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\shunen.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\shunen.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tashi: Incognito Airbender]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Artist: completely forgot, can't find anywhere<br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="lib\media\sora-icon.png">  **Tashi** is an Air Nomad pretending to be a Sandbender, imitating the earth sub-bending forms well. His specialty is blinding/suffocating, used to avoid direct combat. He practices his Air Nomad customs helping however he can while incognito.

(WIP: add details) Tashi is an Air Nomad pretending to be a Sandbender, imitating the earth sub-bending forms well. His specialty is blinding/suffocating, used to avoid direct combat. He practices his Air Nomad customs helping however he can while incognito.
(WIP: add details) <br><img alt="sora source.png" src="lib\media\sora-source.png"> <img alt="sora 2.png" src="lib\media\sora-2.png">]]></description><link>projects\avatar\characters\tashi.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Characters/Tashi.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:09:35 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\sora-icon.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\sora-icon.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Art Style]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>(TODO: add RUMBLE VR, BoTW and Boy and the Heron reference imagery and description)<br><img src="projects\avatar\assets\graphics-test.png"><br>The above screenshot is a Godot Engine 4 example map containing stylized assets and an Azula MMD model with a cel/toon shading effect on her textures. <br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://github.com/RPicster/godot4-demo-desert-light"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"><span></span></div></div></a>GitHub - RPicster/godot4-demo-desert-light: A graphics demo for Godot 4 - Focus is Volumetric Fog and Indirect IlluminationA graphics demo for Godot 4 - Focus is Volumetric Fog and Indirect Illumination - RPicster/godot4-demo-desert-lightgithub.com<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="https://repository-images.githubusercontent.com/643621533/e0b049fa-4983-4184-b1e6-7c920f7dddc6" draggable="false"><br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://www.deviantart.com/k-keii/art/MMD-Princess-Azula-Download-884151175"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"><span></span></div></div></a>MMD Princess Azula Download by k-keii on DeviantArtwww.deviantart.com<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="https://images-wixmp-ed30a86b8c4ca887773594c2.wixmp.com/f/3bacb19c-7e13-4fb6-8af6-36163689b7c0/dg1kx65-d58f7d15-6a7f-42da-aa2d-a752c346f091.png/v1/fill/w_1060,h_754,q_70,strp/zuko_and_azula_by_k_keii_dg1kx65-pre.jpg?token=eyJ0eXAiOiJKV1QiLCJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJzdWIiOiJ1cm46YXBwOjdlMGQxODg5ODIyNjQzNzNhNWYwZDQxNWVhMGQyNmUwIiwiaXNzIjoidXJuOmFwcDo3ZTBkMTg4OTgyMjY0MzczYTVmMGQ0MTVlYTBkMjZlMCIsIm9iaiI6W1t7ImhlaWdodCI6Ijw9MjcyOSIsInBhdGgiOiJcL2ZcLzNiYWNiMTljLTdlMTMtNGZiNi04YWY2LTM2MTYzNjg5YjdjMFwvZGcxa3g2NS1kNThmN2QxNS02YTdmLTQyZGEtYWEyZC1hNzUyYzM0NmYwOTEucG5nIiwid2lkdGgiOiI8PTM4NDAifV1dLCJhdWQiOlsidXJuOnNlcnZpY2U6aW1hZ2Uub3BlcmF0aW9ucyJdfQ.mJ8CVdh1v3RRZfFTnVY37ApK2-Qq7CvzKpT55Y-ehpY" draggable="false"><br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://godotshaders.com/shader/flexible-toon-shader-godot-4/"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"><span></span></div></div></a>Flexible Toon Shader (Godot 4) - Godot ShadersOriginal shader by CaptainProton42 ported to Godot 4 &nbsp; 🤸Flexibility...godotshaders.com<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="http://godotshaders.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screenshot-3.png" draggable="false"><br><br><img alt="rtxsun warriors" src="projects\avatar\assets\rtx-sun-warriors.jpg"><br><img alt="rtx waterbender" src="projects\avatar\assets\rtx-waterbender.png"><br>This was the clickbait "RTX Unreal Engine 5 Trending on Artstation PS6 AAA Open-World RPG" lookin ahh thumbnail for a YT video about the upcoming official Avatar game that takes place a couple thousand years ago called "Avatar: Ice Wars".<br>Upcoming games, whether concept trailer projects or AAA productions like this one, taking the realism approach for attention is inevitable. The UE5 revolution made beautifully realistic lighting accessible to the random asset kitbasher. At this point, even bigger studios are dropping games and trailers that use reskinned existing UE movement engines. Its eye-catching and looks impressive with very little work or creativity.<br>This also appeals to lots of naive gamers with a very generic idea of what an "objectively good game" looks like and plays like, which is 30+ hours of story/resource grind with a flashy light/heavy combo combat system and expansive skill tree (check <a class="internal-link" data-href="#Gameplay" href="about:blank#Gameplay" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Gameplay</a>). This is a safe bet for AAA studios that can dump a set huge amount of money, just pump out assets and people will eat it up for $60.<br>As <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rZlx5vU4tSo" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rZlx5vU4tSo" target="_blank">Drew Gooden</a> claims about the adaptation, Netflix chose spectacle over storytelling in their live-action. I don't like this overall trend of applying the new-gen formula to animated masterpieces like they're doing with Disney classics and anime. Even modern remasters of video games that remain stylized, like Ocarina of Time and Persona 3, lose the mood and color tones that make the games special, in my opinion. It's very clear we lose the soul and, ironically, the life during this process.<br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H_gF2nddVU"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"><span></span></div></div></a>Avatar: ICE WARS™ AAA RPG (PS5) OFFICIAL UPDATE! Story, Customization, Open World Explained &amp; More!Avatar The Last Airbender™ is getting an Open World AAA RPG Game Developed by Saber Interactive &amp; Paramount Game Studios &amp; is coming in 2027/2028 to PC &amp; Consoles. We Breakdown everything about The New Avatar Last Airbender Open World RPG Video Game from New Details of the Main Story, Side Quests, Setting, Location &amp; Open World. Avatar: Ice Wars AAA RPG will feature a Create Your Own Character &amp; Feature Gameplay to Master The Four Elements in an Action RPG Game that is in early development.www.youtube.com]]></description><link>projects\avatar\art-style.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Art Style.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:39:22 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="projects\avatar\assets\graphics-test.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;projects\avatar\assets\graphics-test.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Avatar Tai Prewrite]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Writer: troyoboyo17<br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="projects\avatar\assets\avatar-tai-solo.png">  The Earth Kingdom, scarred by Kuvira's rule, has descended into a totalitarian state under a new Earth King. This new regime exploits the next Avatar, Tai, a sixteen-year-old Earthbender, as a weapon. Brainwashed and indoctrinated, Tai is unaware of his actions while in the Avatar State, used by the Earth King for conquest.

[\[Watch the video\]](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oLMwSpeErKw) or [\[Read the summary\]](Avatar%20Tai.md#Story) The Earth Kingdom, scarred by Kuvira's rule, has descended into a totalitarian state under a new Earth King. This new regime exploits the next Avatar, Tai, a sixteen-year-old Earthbender, as a weapon. Brainwashed and indoctrinated, Tai is unaware of his actions while in the Avatar State, used by the Earth King for conquest.
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oLMwSpeErKw" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oLMwSpeErKw" target="_blank">[Watch the video]</a> or <a class="internal-link" data-href="Avatar Tai.md#Story" href="projects\avatar\avatar-tai.html#Story" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">[Read the summary]</a> <br><br><img src="projects\avatar\assets\avatar-tai.png"><br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oLMwSpeErKw"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"></div></div></a>Fanboy Prewrites "The Next Avatar"...I think that the original series was so beloved for so many reasons, and the goal of this show should be to try and recapture that spirit for a new era. So here’s my pitch for “The Next Avatar.”<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/oLMwSpeErKw/maxresdefault.jpg" draggable="false"><br>The following is essentially a summary/rewrite of the contents of this video, with the writer's commentary mixed with mine in the <a class="internal-link" data-href="#Commentary" href="about:blank#Commentary" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Commentary</a> section below. I'd recommend either watching this video then reading the commentary or just read this full page.<br>Premise: Ninety years after the events of Legend of Korra, the world faces a new threat from within the Earth Kingdom. Earth King Wu's attempts at establishing democracy was flawed and failed. Despite Kuvira's defeat, her ideals of strength and control resonate with many, leading to the rise of a new Earth King who exploits these fears and radicalization of lots of the civilians. Knowing Korra stood in his way and anticipating the next Avatar will be an Earthbender, he waited for her peaceful death before enacting his plan. This plan involves expanding Ba Sing Se's walls, reinstating the Dai Li with absolute control, and conscripting Earthbender children into a brainwashed military force. Republic City is now treated as Aang's undermining of Earth Kingdom authority. The other nations, fearing another war, remain complacent, hoping the next Avatar will intervene.<br>The Earth Empire's Rise: This new Earth Kingdom, effectively Kuvira's Empire all over again, exiles people from surrounding nations and imprisons/brainwashes dissenting civilians, benders and non-benders alike. Republic City, once a symbol of innovation and diversity, is conquered under the guise of protection. The Earth King deliberately avoids searching for the new Avatar, hoping to prevent interference.<br>Tai's Introduction: Tai, a sixteen-year-old Dai Li trainee raised in Ba Sing Se, is raised on the Earth Kingdom's propaganda, never having been outside city walls. He's never seen battle yet trains daily as a child soldier to defend the greatest country. The Dai Li's job is to ensure greatness and serves as the bedrock of their nation. He is fun, easy-going and free-spirited like Aang, the opposite of his element like Korra was. He and his older brother-like friend, Kenshi, encounter Dai Li bullies robbing a Cabbage Man. These three have been harassing Tai all his life. While chasing one down, Tai accidentally separates from Kenshi and once the other bullies catch up and outnumber him, he accidentally firebends while fighting in desperation, revealing his identity as the Avatar.<br>The Weaponized Avatar: Earth Kingdom officials are immediately notified and they work to exploit Tai's power, attempting to weaponize the Avatar. Iroh taught us how each nation embodies different fundamental ideals. Understanding them helps understand the world and one's self holistically. Thus, while lacking diverse bending masters and due to modern Ba Sing Se's echo chamber nature, Tai's firebending is underdeveloped at his best, let alone attempting water or airbending. However, through months of experimentation and brainwashing, they can now successfully activate the Avatar State on command, turning Tai into an instrument of destruction. As a thoroughly-indoctrinated loyal Earth Kingdom soldier, he consents to being used this way but mainly because he has no recollection of his actions during the blackouts. He believes the Earth King's will is his purpose as the Avatar. In contrast to a messiah-type figure who brings balance to the world, the Avatar is now a symbol of fear and death.<br>Korra's Intervention: One night, Tai encounters a shadowed figure. He calls out but the man, without response, spreads his arms and turns the surrounding ground to lava. Tai exhausts his skills defensively fighting the man until Tai's eyes start to glow. "Korra, it really is you," the man says, now revealed as Bolin. Temporarily replaced by Korra's spirit,  Tai replies, "Good to see you again, Bolin." Bolin shows Tai the suffering his actions have caused while under the Earth King's control. This revelation mirrors Iroh and Zuko's respective journeys of guilt and redemption, posing the question of how an Avatar grapples with such responsibility. Due to the experimentation and brainwashing, Tai doesn't have control over the Avatar State but his attunement to Raava and the Spirit World allows easier communication with Korra, without needing to enter the Spirit World or to meditate. She is able to observe and communicate with Tai as well as show herself on special occasions. We see how much she's matured while serving as a guiding hand to Tai, a somewhat active participant from now on.<br>Escape from Ba Sing Se: Bolin, now much older and part of the New Freedom Fighters movement (along with Jinora, Asami and/or Mako), has been secretly searching for the Avatar in Ba Sing Se. He's lost a lot of his humor and personality after witnessing so many horrors but seeing Korra again brought back some of his life. He smuggles Tai outside the Ba Sing Se walls to see innocent people dead or in cages, oppressed by those supposedly keeping them safe. He even witnesses the aftermath of raw power from an impossible force: himself. Seeing and accepting the truth through lifelong indoctrination can be a long and slow process sometimes but tragedy has a way of instantly clearing the fog. Either way, the result is the same and so is the one path to redemption and overcoming his newfound guilt. Bolin reveals a hidden young sky bison to help Tai escape to a firebending master. Tai confronts Kenshi about everything, who's silence admits to knowing the truth and he begins to defend the Earth Kingdom's actions. Kenshi refuses to leave because the Earth King put in an order for something big: a massive, full-scale expansion to grow their home and share it with the rest of the world... starting with the Southern Water Tribe. Tai fully understands what this is: an invasion. Another hundred-year war. Heartbroken by his friend's betrayal, Tai attempts to escape, leading to a fight with Kenshi in which he's fighting defensively and nearly captured. Bolin intervenes, allowing Tai to flee on the bison while he watches Bolin get beaten and arrested.<br>The Journey Begins: Tai, now alone with the guidance of Korra's spirit, begins his journey to right the Earth Kingdom's wrongs and rebuild the Avatar's reputation, witnessing destruction firsthand and fights driven by guilt and a sense of justice to help people. He aims to reconnect with his past lives, starting with Aang, whose fractured spirit resides in the spirit world in his child form with fragmented memories due to the severed connection. As Tai meditates at Aang's important places (southern air temple, where zuko saved him as the blue spirit, ruins of republic city where he proposed to katara, where tenzin first learned airbending, where he buried appa?) and revisits relevant characters (ko the face stealer, heibai, painted lady, yue, maybe iroh), Aang ages up visibly each time as flashbacks restore his memories. He is forced to accept that his efforts in stopping the Fire Nation and bringing balance wasn't permanent; the rise of fascism and the cycle of violence are constants that need to be actively observed and countered ahead of time. <br>The Rest of the Series:  The show explores themes of historical repetition, fascism's enduring nature, and the dangers of complacency. The series will follow Tai's travels, similarly guided by and restoring connections with past Avatar spirits, to master the elements and confront the Earth Kingdom's regime. A major tactic of fascism is eliminating history, hence the focus on reconnecting with past lives and staying in contact with history. Kenshi, blamed for Tai's escape thus now tasked with hunting him, teases a potential redemption arc during a tragic descent into unwavering loyalty, like She-Ra's sisters turned bitter enemies. Tai may eventually have to accept that not everyone can change. Tai will challenge the leaders of the other nations for their inaction, as it now exacerbated the problem to this level. You cant wait till violence affects you personally to care because by that point, it'll be too late.<br><br>This fanon is interesting because it can be applied to both the Earth and Fire Avatars following Korra. For example, I doubt the canon Earth Avatar will be born as Dai Li but the themes of indoctrination and weaponization apply heavily to combustion-benders. It explores the common question, what if the Avatar was born on the wrong side? The young Avatars and Dai Li/Unanimity companions will be brainwashed into sleeper agents and their Avatar states taken under control. Whether their philosophies will echo their oppressors is more likely as a soldier than a convict and dependent on how well the different propaganda they're fed aligns with their personal experiences.<br>Avatar has always been political. The first movie is very anti-fascist and all the villains in Korra represent a different ideology. Since the canon Earth Avatars are gonna be young children, there's a chance they'll take the totalitarian regime route again like Ozai, Kuvira and this new Earth King<br>The overall concept of this story is very similar to ATLA's Hundred-Year War and Kuvira's Earth Empire. Thought we should embrace change like Korra instead of attempting to be a carbon copy of the OG Avatar, this case is by design since the theme is "history repeats itself". The use of a sky bison, or a similar hybrid companion, is considered for branding and practicality for the writer (a "home base" and traveling loop is useful for the episodic format).<br>He intentionally avoids recreating the original "Gaang" dynamic even though it was one of the keys of the OG show's success, focusing on Tai's solitary journey as one way to set this Avatar adventure different. Also, he wants to include familiar elements and characters but avoid excessive fan service so the New Freedom Fighter inclusions and the character revisit selections for Aang's memories should be meticulous.<br>I agree with the Earth Avatar's overarching challenge being to correct Korra's mistakes: re-establish connections with the past Avatars and address the conflicts regarding the new spirit portal. Similarly, we have to speculate which mistakes this/any Earth avatar would make and set that as the Fire Avatar's main goal to correct.<br>I think it's unrealistic for the Earth King to let the Avatar go undiscovered, regardless of "neutral jing" philosophy, because this is an ineffective way to minimize the Avatar's inevitable interference. In a controlling regime, the expected course of action in my opinion would be to find and weaponize the next Avatar thus: have a surveillance network that would notify one's rise, have a foolproof abduction method always ready and actively use all Avatar seeking methods to locate them. The last and most important one isn't being employed by the writer.]]></description><link>projects\avatar\avatar-tai.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Avatar Tai.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:08:33 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="projects\avatar\assets\avatar-tai-solo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;projects\avatar\assets\avatar-tai-solo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Avatar Shunen]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Style: Sifu<br>
Movement/Combat: For Honor<br>
Engine: Godot 4<br>This project was born for three reasons:<br>
<br>Easter Egg: Combustion-bending tattoos would glow in the Avatar state like Air Master tattoos because its on a chi path (presumably the Third Eye chakra, inspired by Hindu God Shiva's symbol)
<br>Unique Combat: I doubt Avatar Studios will create a game with the radically different combat system and tailored control scheme that the bending arts deserve
<br>ATLA's Vision: The original show established a mythical awe in the Avatar State, bending philosophy and rich cultural diversity. Let's bring that back.
<br><br>This lore expands on and references the full Avatar lore. To catch up on all the official releases, read up on the accepted theories and explore the accepted (canon-parallel/non-conflicting) fan projects, <a class="internal-link" data-href="Canon.md" href="projects\avatar\canon.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">skim the Context page</a>. Here's some excerpts:<br><br><br><br>Comics<br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLDf5wY6_w38EOKvK2MKmcT3JFUhGPuvMd" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLDf5wY6_w38EOKvK2MKmcT3JFUhGPuvMd" target="_blank">Book 4 Restoration: Motion Comic (voice-acted, incomplete)</a> :: some episodes are fanon filler
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL0uuU7hMyKdUfuQKPaYye4k-Ayt320s97" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL0uuU7hMyKdUfuQKPaYye4k-Ayt320s97" target="_blank">Official Motion Comic (summarized, incomplete)</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.webtoons.com/en/fantasy/avatar-the-last-airbender/list?title_no=6205" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.webtoons.com/en/fantasy/avatar-the-last-airbender/list?title_no=6205" target="_blank">Readable for free on Webtoons (incomplete)</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.reddit.com/r/TheLastAirbender/comments/cmw4bd/how_to_get_into_the_comics/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/TheLastAirbender/comments/cmw4bd/how_to_get_into_the_comics/" target="_blank">Read order</a> for physical/kindle copies and <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B087R35G65" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B087R35G65" target="_blank">where to buy them</a>
<br>Rise of Kyoski (Kyoshi 1/2) novel<br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLOE7qBj7RtTLX4Dg8FI3o9gkrVmniYaqt" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLOE7qBj7RtTLX4Dg8FI3o9gkrVmniYaqt" target="_blank">Rise of Kyoshi Visual Novel (voice-acted, incomplete, unofficial art)</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://linktr.ee/avatargenerations" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://linktr.ee/avatargenerations" target="_blank">Official Avatar Generations Game (not 1:1, incomplete, canon art)</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07X1QBC2D?binding=hardcover&amp;searchxofy=true" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07X1QBC2D?binding=hardcover&amp;searchxofy=true" target="_blank">Physical, kindle and audiobook forms</a><br>
Shadow of Kyoshi (2/2) novel and Yangchen/Roku novels
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07X1QBC2D?binding=hardcover&amp;searchxofy=true" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07X1QBC2D?binding=hardcover&amp;searchxofy=true" target="_blank">Physical, kindle and audiobook forms</a>
<br>(The following is WIP)<br>
Legacy:<br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://atla-lore-archive.tumblr.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://atla-lore-archive.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">Lost Lore of Aang</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.tumblr.com/tloklorearchive" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.tumblr.com/tloklorearchive" target="_blank">Lost Lore of Korra</a><br>
Other: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.reddit.com/r/TheLastAirbender/comments/cqarck/canon_beyond_the_shows_and_comics/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/TheLastAirbender/comments/cqarck/canon_beyond_the_shows_and_comics/" target="_blank">Reddit post</a><br>
The Tabletop Roleplaying Game (books and booklets)
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://avatar.fandom.com/wiki/Category:Avatar_Legends:_The_Roleplaying_Game_playbooks" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://avatar.fandom.com/wiki/Category:Avatar_Legends:_The_Roleplaying_Game_playbooks" target="_blank">Avatar Legends RPG booklet cover characters</a>
<br><br><br><br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://failingradish.tumblr.com/tagged/giving%20past%20avatar%20a%20face" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://failingradish.tumblr.com/tagged/giving%20past%20avatar%20a%20face" target="_blank">Giving Past Avatar A Face</a>: Lore/art on lots of past Avatars
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://avatarhanami.tumblr.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://avatarhanami.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">Avatar: New Beginnings</a>: The Second Avatar Hanami, airbender following Wan
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.webtoons.com/en/canvas/avatar-the-flames-of-kaiya/list?title_no=947868" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.webtoons.com/en/canvas/avatar-the-flames-of-kaiya/list?title_no=947868" target="_blank">The Flames of Kaiya</a>: Story after Avatar: TLA's finale
<br>Even though the Avatar Tai prewrite wasn't accepted as "canon" for this lore like the projects above, it heavily influenced writing decisions for this projects so I highly recommend everyone either watch the video then read the commentary at the bottom of the document or (recommended) just read the full document instead.<br><br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="projects\avatar\assets\avatar-tai-solo.png">   The Earth Kingdom, scarred by Kuvira's rule, has descended into a totalitarian state under a new Earth King. This new regime exploits the next Avatar, Tai, a sixteen-year-old Earthbender, as a weapon. Brainwashed and indoctrinated, Tai is unaware of his actions while in the Avatar State, used by the Earth King for conquest.
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oLMwSpeErKw" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oLMwSpeErKw" target="_blank">[Watch the video]</a> or <a class="internal-link" data-href="Avatar Tai.md#Story" href="projects\avatar\avatar-tai.html#Story" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">[Read the summary]</a> <br><br><img src="projects\avatar\assets\moodboard-ss.png"><br>If you want to check out the reference material (fanart and official art) for fresh fashion/character designs, <a class="internal-link" data-href="Moodboard.canvas" href="projects\avatar\moodboard.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">check out the Moodboard page</a>.<br><br>Here's some reference music albums/mixes related to Avatar's tone/origins and their respective contexts. I recommend putting one on while reading this document to set the mood.<br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VIVfOCd04BA"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"><span></span></div></div></a>[Ambience] Yingying - Chinese Guqin relaxing classical musicThe Chinese guqin is a plucked seven-string instrument of the zither family, sometimes referred to as "the instrument of the sages" associated with refinement, literati and sometimes with the philosopher, Confucius.www.youtube.com<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="https://i.postimg.cc/23RWPzwM/guqin-album-art.png" draggable="false"><br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PDLDqh0Xpew"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"><span></span></div></div></a>[Tension] Java - Gamelans From The Sultan's Palace In JogjakartaGamelan is the traditional ensemble music of the Javanese, Sundanese, and Balinese peoples of Indonesia, made up predominantly of percussive instruments: metallophones played by mallets and a set of hand-played drums called kendhang which register the beat.www.youtube.com<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="https://i.postimg.cc/TwsgJjWR/gamelans-album-art.jpg" draggable="false"><br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h1Yjmbc6768"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"><span></span></div></div></a>[Battle] Joffre Videz - Taiko DeliriumTaiko or wadaiko indicate a variety of Eastern percussion intruments such as nagadō-daiko (large barrel-shaped), and others like the shime-daiko (smaller). Taiko is associated with Japanese mythology but may have been introduced through Chinese/Korean influence.www.youtube.com<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="https://i.postimg.cc/8crWKFhL/taiko-album-art.jpg" draggable="false"><br><br><img alt="style ref" src="projects\avatar\assets\style-ref.jpeg"><br>(WIP: add new prelude lore during Earth avatar generation)<br>(WIP: MC's parents lore, upbringing before/during Unanimity)<br>Lore above will appear to the viewer later in the story via character dialogue, environment design or PTSD flashback imagery.<br><br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="projects\avatar\assets\shunen.jpg">   Shunen is a combustion bender who was captured at a young age from his Air Nomad mother and survived the Unanimity trials until he escaped at 16.  He regularly risked exploring the facility, against the threat of solitary confinement, electrocution and/or "reprogramming." He is nimble, empathetic, resilient and hyper-vigilant. He used his prodigious firebending, with an affinity for speed, to defend helpless inmates. <br><br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="projects\avatar\assets\monzart_airbender.jpg">   Shu Ming is Shunen's mother. She was incredibly spritually-attuned able to spiritually project and enter the Spirit World (a Spirit Library scholar). That was before Shunen was concieved with a firebending father who left when things went downhill: her bending became weaker, her health/self-love declined and she lost her spiritual abilities. Despite it all, she was always an incredibly loving and caring mother, sister and helper. After Shunen's capture, she fell apart and started using fans to maintain her dying bending. <br><br><br>(WIP: break out on episode 2, spend time showing the injustice of the camp before ramping up)<br>MC begins in a combustion bending camp off the record from any government authorities, thus technologically outdated. Owners unknown and the workers appear to be non-benders armed with Equalist-style tech. His mother taught him effective breathing techniques for meditation which is the only reason little Shunen got this far.<br><br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="projects\avatar\assets\yuyan-combustion-icon.png">   Jin is a stoic yuyan archer captured for Unanimity who maintains his vow of silence throughout. He begins as a weak victimized character with a starved medium-tall stature during his appearance in Unanimity, no tattoo. He reappears in the future as a full-on Unanimity mercenary who completed his training and is loyal enough to his 'contractors' to one day encounter Shunen again as an opponent until they recognize each other. <br>MC has a big brother figure due to their friendly history but he's a complete asshole these days that regularly switches up abruptly. We observe the pain this causes MC who always tries to trust him and has love for him. MC is constantly defending the people who get picked on and thus gets targetted too but no one defends him. He's been punished many times for fighting and for trespassing by electric shock, solitary confinement, "reprogramming" or anything the guard thought would be funny. He's done some airbending and earthbending subtly like breaking a chunk of stone off that held his binding chain underwater or exhaled supernaturally hard and blown someone far away off their footing while strapped to a chair but nothing irrefutably Avatar-like.<br>That's until they took it too far with brutally and unfairly punishing him and Ajna, the go-to victim for extreme bullying. The bigger inmates are always willing to dish out freshly burnt limbs on a whim, scars under handwraps and clothes to prove it. Having recently become 16, Ajna goes into the Avatar State for the first time and leaves the camp torn apart with knocked out bodies lining the floor (only bullies and guards, no one killed) before busting out. (edit: add details)<br><br>MC wakes up dehydrated and horribly sunburnt somewhere in the Si Wong Desert, dumbfounded of how he got here having forgotten the Avatar state situation entirely. He starts walking towards dig site for shelter as it starts getting dark. Unbeknownst to him, this is the Wan Shi Ton library excavation site (commissioned by Jarvis Sato) but the library is now in the Spirit World and thus the project was abandoned. Once he gets there, he sees sandbenders whom he shoots a fireball above them to get their attention, then shoots upwards in a pattern to indicate location.<br><br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="projects\avatar\assets\sora-icon.png">   Tashi is an Air Nomad pretending to be a Sandbender, imitating the earth sub-bending forms well. His specialty is blinding/suffocating, used to avoid direct combat. He practices his Air Nomad customs helping however he can while incognito.
(WIP: add details) <br><br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="projects\avatar\assets\kaliph-icon.png">   The Kaliph is teated like a spiritual leader in the Si Wong settlement. His specialty is mudbending which he uses like Kuvira/Dai Lee. He has an unusually large body and a wheezy, harsh voice that he uses very sparingly due to a burn injury on the throat and upper body. Adorned in jewelry and wrapped like a mummy, his status was earned by helping build the settlement from the ground up and resolving conflicts with a heavy hand. He carries a sword and gourd of mud. <br>Tashi is the disrespected young guy of the sandbenders who's always doing the labor of powering the sand-sailer. He asks everyone to split their portion of water since everyone is running low but they force him to give MC his whole portion. They mock him for acting air nomad like, joking about what they'd do if they "get [their] hands on one of those Nomad girls" out of earshot of the boss and asks MC for trade for ride to their settlement. He has nothing so he offers labor (to boost the sailer from behind with firebending (goes to the back of the sailer, grabs the edge and demonstrates with a light fire blast) but leader uses Kuvira/Dai Lee-style technique to bind his hands with rings (first flashback, Kuvira binding Korra) made from quickly ejected mud from his gourd and hardened. He raises MC's arms overhead and says 'winds' holding his other hand out then says 'burn' while pointing at the wooden deck then says 'trade'.<br>MC gives them his prison clothes. They all laugh but the leader who accepts and they start mounting the vehicle but they see the fin of a sand shark fast approaching, to which they start rushing to head to town. (edit: add details to fight) During the fight, Tashi is forced to protect the sailer with airbending. Leader sees this and Tashi looks at him worried but now freely able to use his airbending, they working together, they manage to escape.<br>
After fight, leader calls Tashi a 'liar' and everyone braces to kill him. MC interrupts them while holding large amount of fire over their sailer and says 'trade'.<br>They get kicked off the sailer and are forced to walk to town, Tashi requiring assistance from dehydration. They discuss backstories, Tashi came here on a nomadic mission to help the town but since they dislike outsiders, he kept his airbending cloaked. MC keeps it general wondering if he still remembers his moms face and voice and if/how much she's changed. He's also just bewildered by how he got here, thinking about how drastically his life changed from just yesterday.<br><br><img alt="si wong desert" src="projects\avatar\assets\si-wong-desert.jpg"><br>Tashi says they can speak to the kaliph if they have something to offer so he thinks of trading his airbending sailer, which he digs out from it's hiding spot, for a small transport vehicle to outside the desert. Tashi's done his time here, he believes. MC wants to find his mom so he wants to get to the closest woman's air temple. Once they arrive in town, people there are a bit nicer, lots of talk about the kaliph being a fair/honest man worldbuilding but unwelcoming to newcomers.<br>MC helps town somehow with firebending? (edit: add details, people's negative reaction turn positive?). They give him some clothes to wear. This news inevitably gets to the kaliph. Tashi and MC goes to sleep in his pathetic DIY tent after splitting the small amount of vegetarian foods Tashi collected. MC wakes up during sandstorm, most of which was shielded by the houses surrounding them. Tashi's still asleep and he goes back to sleep after the storm dies down.<br>Next day, they await the kaliph's audience for hours as people go in and out of the grand stone building until they're called. They bring the staff in as an offering, speaking of its emotional significance, and bows his head. He says "rise". They realize who it is from the voice so they look up and we see him unwrapped: burns all over exposed neck area, stitching on throat. He stays silent then points at MC "you helped". He gestures to a helper who takes the staff and the kaliph says "small" before they leave. Leads them to an isolated small diseased elephant-camel with a fucked up face and smells nauseating.<br>They're given just enough water and they set off that night, the water container and shelter supplies mounted on the creature. MC's unanimity/airbender breath training paid off as he doesn't get that exhausted while walking the long distances while controlling his breathing. They take turns riding it whom they named Cocoa for its abnormal chocolatey color. He uses breath of fire to warm them up citing his moms teaching about true firebending, though he usually just uses raw resolve to fuel his bending. Cocoa drains cactus juice with tusk and Tashi makes a joke about not drinking that, then he picks out the spikes and helps the little animal eat it. He explains to MC that elephant-camels can usually eat these without help. All three vegetarians share the cactus, disgusting/disorienting but filling.<br>Eventually they set up camp. This time, they both wake up as they get the full fury of a sandstorm which destroys their shelter. They sleep out in the open in the scorching heat. (edit: other encounters in the desert that justifies why everyone doesn't just leave) They travel like this for days and days.<br>Once they get to the nearest haven, they find that the newcomer/homeless system is pretty good because the previous avatar's street urchin upbringing lead them to focus on building out accommodations for the less fortunate. Cocoa is brought to healers and they are mostly able to heal him but they had to remove an eye. Tashi jokes about how they should've named him Zuko but "the scar is on the wrong side" but MC doesn't know who that is.<br><br>(WIP: They make their way to the Western (?) Air Temple; This should be full of people from all walks of life and different in other ways due to Haven system)<br><br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="projects\avatar\assets\nymia-icon.png">   Samaya is passionate about dancing, arts and cooking great vegetarian food. She is a soft-spoken respectful yet confident and talkative girl with a playful teasing nature who's found peace from within herself and from nature, a stark contrast from MC but he warms up quickly and indulges the banter (she's the big sister he never had). She is often found enjoying views alone while holding various impressive acrobatic poses effortlessly or hanging out with Mei Lin. She obtained her mastery tattoos at 19. <br><br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="projects\avatar\assets\air-acolyte.webp">   Mei Lin visited the Western Air Temple just because the Nomad visitors in her town were "so pretty and nice" and though she didn't really take to all the customs (quite materialistic and cares too much about her appearance), she decided to stay and everyone loves her joyous energy tempered with charisma and elegance. She especially enjoys Samaya's company. She is an Earth-born non-bender Air Acolyte who loves yoga and gardening but hates meditating. <br><br><br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="projects\avatar\assets\red-spirit.jpg">   Inspired by the Blue Spirit of legend who saved the Air Avatar past, the Red Spirit alter ego was born. With her Kusarigama, she can crowd control with intimidation and unpredictability. She can use the chain side as a whip to shatter bones (gunshot sound) or tangle it around sword hilts and legs if a weight or mini-hook is attached. She accrues a Robin Hood-like reputation in her area with a heavy bounty on her head. <br><br><br><img class="avatar svelte-okpkt8" alt="Avatar" src="projects\avatar\assets\jarvis-sato-icon.png">   A spiritual successor to Amon, Jarvis Sato masterminds a brand new Equalist movement with his Future Industries CTO money. He obtained a spirit world equivalent of Jennamite which he surgically bound to his chest and it lightly burrowed through his body forming a symbiotic relationship, most of the initial growth surgically removed. As long as his tech keeps it stabilized, his energy-hungry suit can channel it's power. <br><br><img src="projects\avatar\assets\moveset.jpg"><br>(WIP: Replace with updated moveset after completion)<br><br><img alt="graphics test" src="projects\avatar\assets\graphics-test.png"><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="Art Style.md" href="projects\avatar\art-style.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Click to view details</a>]]></description><link>projects\avatar\blueprint.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Blueprint.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 08:22:13 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="projects\avatar\assets\avatar-tai-solo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;projects\avatar\assets\avatar-tai-solo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Canon]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>Comics<br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLDf5wY6_w38EOKvK2MKmcT3JFUhGPuvMd" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLDf5wY6_w38EOKvK2MKmcT3JFUhGPuvMd" target="_blank">Book 4 Restoration: Motion Comic (voice-acted, incomplete)</a> :: some episodes are fanon filler
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL0uuU7hMyKdUfuQKPaYye4k-Ayt320s97" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL0uuU7hMyKdUfuQKPaYye4k-Ayt320s97" target="_blank">Official Motion Comic (summarized, incomplete)</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.webtoons.com/en/fantasy/avatar-the-last-airbender/list?title_no=6205" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.webtoons.com/en/fantasy/avatar-the-last-airbender/list?title_no=6205" target="_blank">Readable for free on Webtoons (incomplete)</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.reddit.com/r/TheLastAirbender/comments/cmw4bd/how_to_get_into_the_comics/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/TheLastAirbender/comments/cmw4bd/how_to_get_into_the_comics/" target="_blank">Read order</a> for physical/kindle copies and <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B087R35G65" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B087R35G65" target="_blank">where to buy them</a>
<br>Rise of Kyoski (Kyoshi 1/2) novel<br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLOE7qBj7RtTLX4Dg8FI3o9gkrVmniYaqt" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLOE7qBj7RtTLX4Dg8FI3o9gkrVmniYaqt" target="_blank">Rise of Kyoshi Visual Novel (voice-acted, incomplete, unofficial art)</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://linktr.ee/avatargenerations" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://linktr.ee/avatargenerations" target="_blank">Official Avatar Generations Game (not 1:1, incomplete, canon art)</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07X1QBC2D?binding=hardcover&amp;searchxofy=true" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07X1QBC2D?binding=hardcover&amp;searchxofy=true" target="_blank">Physical, kindle and audiobook forms</a><br>
Shadow of Kyoshi (2/2) novel and Yangchen/Roku novels
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07X1QBC2D?binding=hardcover&amp;searchxofy=true" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07X1QBC2D?binding=hardcover&amp;searchxofy=true" target="_blank">Physical, kindle and audiobook forms</a>
<br>(The following is WIP)<br>
Legacy:<br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://atla-lore-archive.tumblr.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://atla-lore-archive.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">Lost Lore of Aang</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.tumblr.com/tloklorearchive" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.tumblr.com/tloklorearchive" target="_blank">Lost Lore of Korra</a><br>
Other: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.reddit.com/r/TheLastAirbender/comments/cqarck/canon_beyond_the_shows_and_comics/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/TheLastAirbender/comments/cqarck/canon_beyond_the_shows_and_comics/" target="_blank">Reddit post</a><br>
The Tabletop Roleplaying Game (books and booklets)
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://avatar.fandom.com/wiki/Category:Avatar_Legends:_The_Roleplaying_Game_playbooks" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://avatar.fandom.com/wiki/Category:Avatar_Legends:_The_Roleplaying_Game_playbooks" target="_blank">Avatar Legends RPG booklet cover characters</a>
<br><br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zj6p5kYnPPY" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zj6p5kYnPPY" target="_blank">The Red Lotus has a point: The Avatar's mistakes - Film Theory</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1g7vSFtkLgwoZAyVVubo9gXac-6pdA685ZH3uZFSlG-k/edit?pli=1&amp;tab=t.0" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1g7vSFtkLgwoZAyVVubo9gXac-6pdA685ZH3uZFSlG-k/edit?pli=1&amp;tab=t.0" target="_blank">Ty Lee was an Air Nomad descendant - @avatar_yangchen</a>
<br><br><br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://failingradish.tumblr.com/tagged/giving%20past%20avatar%20a%20face" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://failingradish.tumblr.com/tagged/giving%20past%20avatar%20a%20face" target="_blank">Giving Past Avatar A Face</a>: Lore/art on lots of past Avatars
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://avatarhanami.tumblr.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://avatarhanami.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">Avatar: New Beginnings</a>: The Second Avatar Hanami, airbender following Wan
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.webtoons.com/en/canvas/avatar-the-flames-of-kaiya/list?title_no=947868" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.webtoons.com/en/canvas/avatar-the-flames-of-kaiya/list?title_no=947868" target="_blank">The Flames of Kaiya</a>: Story after Avatar: TLA's finale
<br><br>
<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="AvatarTai.md" href="AvatarTai" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Avatar Tai Prewrite</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://marcusthevisual.com/avatar-legend-of-abioye/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://marcusthevisual.com/avatar-legend-of-abioye/" target="_blank">Legend of Abioye</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://twitter.com/avatarkaichi" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/avatarkaichi" target="_blank">The Era of Kaichi</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.webtoons.com/en/canvas/the-legend-of-genji/list?title_no=194154" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.webtoons.com/en/canvas/the-legend-of-genji/list?title_no=194154" target="_blank">Legend of Genji</a>

<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLHymzaCV7nx_xK7GGkfXJLrApyOfuLDUN" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLHymzaCV7nx_xK7GGkfXJLrApyOfuLDUN" target="_blank">Official Motion Comic (complete)</a>


<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://legendofvahni.tumblr.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://legendofvahni.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">Legend of Vahni</a>
]]></description><link>projects\avatar\canon.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Canon.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 06:35:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Naming Guide]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>This is a rough copy-and-paste of relevant discussion with the White Lotus chat (thanks uriel and nastune, yall are the best)<br>Because fire nation tends to give parts of their name to the kid so if let’s say her name was Yangchen for example the name could be Yangzu of Ryuchen for example<br>Fire Nation characters have given names and clan names. They do not usually mention their clan names when they introduce themselves unless it is relevant to the situation or they are trying to show off for some reason. Families in the Fire Nation often like to pass individual syllables in their names on to one another: a woman named Zaagar might pass one character in her name on to her child or nibling, naming them Daozaa or Garrun. Use one or two syllables below for each given name and clan name. Zaagar breaks down to Zaa and Gar Garrun takes the gar part of her name Daozaa takes the zaa part of her name<br>Given this story takes place in the future they may not do clan names anymore<br>- uriel<br><br>we can also look to tibetan names (gyatso, tenzin, kelsang, jetsun, pema, pasang, tashi) - me<br><br>Google translate isn't very good.<br>
<br>For Chinese, I recommend using this (<a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" title="https://chinese.yabla.com/chinese-english-pinyin-dictionary.php" href="https://chinese.yabla.com/chinese-english-pinyin-dictionary.php" target="_blank">https://chinese.yabla.com/chinese-english-pinyin-dictionary.php</a>) and wiktionary.
<br>For Japanese, <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" title="https://www.romajidesu.com/" href="https://www.romajidesu.com/" target="_blank">https://www.romajidesu.com/</a> and wiktionary.
<br>For Korean, wiktionary and there was a handful of useful wikipedia pages
<br>For Tibetan, there are many resources and many people you can take names from. For checking the meaning and the spelling, use <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" title="https://rywiki.tsadra.org/index.php/Main_Page" href="https://rywiki.tsadra.org/index.php/Main_Page" target="_blank">https://rywiki.tsadra.org/index.php/Main_Page</a> (it has the Buddhist Masters link with many names in categories. Be prepared for strange direct romanizations, though)
<br>For Inuit (Water Tribe names), a variety of sources but try to verify them in some dictionaries
<br>For Mongolian (mostly FN names), bolor toli dictionary <img alt="✨" src="https://discord.com/assets/5df680186a4bdc43d2cc.svg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"> 
<br>General:<br>
<br>wiktionary is your friend
<br>behindthename is a really good one, but double-check if something isn't verified enough
<br>most babynames websites are pretty sketchy, but not 100%. So it's okay to use them foe ideas, but you have to double check things
<br>- nastune<br><br>
btw i saw an airbender character in the wiki 'Malu' which is 'indonesian/malay' for shyness and polynesian for 'gentle/calm wind' - me
<br>
<br>Indonesian - yes, there are some, but can't confirm any Polynesian languages for Avatar world. There are a couple of Hawaiian names, but not commonly. I think those were either for Hira'a village and for non-standard WT people (like pirates or those with URN nationality)
<br>Check out the Names in the World of Avatar page on the avatar wiki, it has a lot of stuff (these pages above helped expand this article, too). Also, there are useful name lists in the RPG core book
<br>- nastune<br><br>Oww they overhauled the useful format of the wikipedia article on Korean names<br>
Anyway, here's the version I found useful:<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" title="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=List_of_Korean_given_names&amp;diff=prev&amp;oldid=1236149527" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=List_of_Korean_given_names&amp;diff=prev&amp;oldid=1236149527" target="_blank">https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=List_of_Korean_given_names&amp;diff=prev&amp;oldid=1236149527</a><br>More:<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" title="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Korean_given_names" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Korean_given_names" target="_blank">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Korean_given_names</a> (atla sometimes uses non-standard romanization)<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" title="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Template:Personal_names" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Template:Personal_names" target="_blank">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Template:Personal_names</a> (East Asian cat., Mongolian, Tibetan, Hawaiian (in special circumstances), and Indosphere cat. are your friends)<br>- nastune<br><br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://atlaculture.tumblr.com/post/715439644484993024/correction-for-an-old-post-vachir-isnt" target="_blank">https://atlaculture.tumblr.com/post/715439644484993024/correction-for-an-old-post-vachir-isnt</a><br>
<br>vachir (sanskrit vajna meaning "thunderbolt/diamond" symbol for masculine energy into mongolian approximation)
<br>uzuku yuyan (japanese/nigerian?) and jujinta are the only other known ones i believe
<br>- me<br><br>Earth nation names<br>
Toph Beifong: chinese for expanding lotus, northern<br>
Kyoshi: japanese for samurai of the capital<br>
Suki: japanese for beloved (unconfirmed)<br>
Kuvira: chinese for security team<br>
Bumi: sanskrit for earth/land<br>
Opal: word originates from sanskrit for jewel<br>
Suyin: chinese for unadorned sound = plain sound/simple tone interpreted as beauty in simplicity<br>
Haru: japanese for spring (dominant season for earthbenders, mention of seasons affecting bending in The Last Airbender: Legacy)<br>
Jianzhu: chinese for building/structure<br>Air nation names<br>
<a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.momjunction.com/articles/tibetan-sherpa-names-girls-boys-meanings_00680269/" target="_blank">https://www.momjunction.com/articles/tibetan-sherpa-names-girls-boys-meanings_00680269/</a><br>- me<br><br>Ham Ghao - Foolish Troublemaker,&nbsp;憨搞 (Cantonese)<br>
Xi - seems chinese, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://chinese.yabla.com/chinese-english-pinyin-dictionary.php?define=xi" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://chinese.yabla.com/chinese-english-pinyin-dictionary.php?define=xi" target="_blank">has many diff meanings</a>]]></description><link>projects\avatar\naming-guide.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Naming Guide.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 10:19:14 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://discord.com/assets/5df680186a4bdc43d2cc.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://discord.com/assets/5df680186a4bdc43d2cc.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Scratchpad]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Ideas: Distrust of authority, phobia of confined spaces (anxiety), lack of sociability (via seclusion; social anxiety), performance anxiety = &lt;100% success rate -&gt; mastery = &gt;100% speed, hyperawareness: insomnia/hallucinations/dissociation/memory fragmentations, survivors guilt, having not seeing water in ages a sip restores a bit of conscious away from feral animal,<br>
Inclusion of feminine coming-of-age struggles like Paper Girls?<br>
How man reacts to impulse define what type of man he is: like lightning redirecting through the body<br>Hideki: Should he have been alexithymic before spirit possession?<br>
False Avatar Yun descended into madness. How does this apply to Arthit/Hideki?<br>
Arthit is like Zaheer, very spiritually in tune but kills people. He is a white lotus in the making. Should Hideki/Sato be Red Lotus?<br>Breath control before launching an ultimate<br>
Yin yang like chi seperation minigame for lightning bending<br>
Since P'li can curve combustion and detonate early, San (yuyan) and Zarya (sun warrior, air-influenced) can get range/microadjustment/breath efficiency buffs in trade for power/curvability/early detonation<br>
Factors: range/microadjustment/breath efficiency/power/curvability/early detonation<br>Zarya's mother didn't adjust well with Air Nomad customs and left. They are medium progressive<br>
Could the sun warriors still be alive? Would they be too hidden to be found by Zarya's mom?<br>
How about Jeong Jeong's tribe?<br>
How would the White and Red Lotus organizations develop? (Black Grandmaster Lotus outfits for the White Lotus would be sick)<br>Sato: Voice sounds like Ultron's with the mask on, Varrick without? Would that be copying Varrick too much?<br>
Color purple like kuvira's spirit root canon blasts. Should the reactor be in the center/right of his chest (aka connected to lungs) or left of his chest (connected to the heart)?<br>
LED brightness should rise and lower with audible breath.<br>After a boss battle, zarya speedrun unlocks the last couple elements as her makeshift family falls apart (death, betrayal, forceful seperation, loss of will to fight) and finally kills her villain and becomes a somewhat realized Avatar but feels like shes left with nothing but a world of responsibility, a bittersweet victory.<br>Compare with Aang/Korra to triangulate: when they get their other elements, when the avatar state is activated for the first time, spirituality curve<br>Avatar's responsibility: correct previous Avatar's mistakes, serve as bridge between humans/spirits<br>
White Lotus: plays a multi-century patience game for the greater good (sometimes goes against the Avatar) -&gt; supports the Avatar to save the world -&gt; protects the Avatar from the Red Lotus<br>
Red Lotus: capture the Avatar to end the cycle<br>Follow the Avatar Tai prewrite trajectory<br>Beast of Spirit Temple contains memories about the Sun Warriors, from Hanami or an actual Sun Warrior-origin Avatar?<br>
Sun warriors in the spirit world make sense because dragons are spirit world animals, especially in an even grander dragon temple. (sky bison present in spirit world?)<br>
Sandbender: Carry a gourd like Gaara?<br>
Age of kidnapping should be after he learns about the bees and knees so the "ending" hits harder<br>Painted Lady? Yue inclusion (intended to be the avatar)?]]></description><link>projects\avatar\scratchpad.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Avatar/Scratchpad.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 22:28:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Eldoria: ADHD RPG with AI guild]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>A webapp where user can interact with different Personas, which are AI agent presets of different LLMs, prompts, functions, appearance and voice<br>Progressively multi-modal interaction, personality trait/social need systems and getting/trading agents will be gamified for retention/profit and immersion. What does this mean?<br><br><br>
<br>Open app to a grid, (2 columns on mobile) vertically long boxes aka Cards

<br>name, level and HQ art (shows where they are/what they're doing)
<br>higher level shows cooler border decorations, animated art, size


<br>Click a card to fullscreen card video for viewing, with details overlay

<br>Persona 5-style social stats show progress until level up/down
<br>preview cosmetic upgrades from future level rewards


<br>Swipe left-right through album, swipe up for msgs, swipe down to go back

<br>unlock more photos in album through levelling/chatting (they'll send)


<br>Messaging screen's top bar buttons:

<br>click name/profile picture to view pfp in fullscreen
<br>voice call/desktop invite when levelled enough and schedule aligns


<br><br>Desktop:<br>
<br>these would all be chibi style frames stitched together like "v-pet simulator"

<br>using stable diffusion, focus on consistency between frames


<br>emotes: think, explain, point, talk, smug, excite, sad, angry, laugh, hate, love
<br>actions: walk, climb, sit, watch monitor, sleep, read book/personality activity<br>
Profile:
<br>these would be generated with midjourney for "hi-fi quality" appearance
<br>pfp: headshot icon with generic bg
<br>album: glamorous fx selfies w/ aesthetic bgs<br>
Card:
<br>these would be Wallpaper Engine style 2 second loop videos

<br>source image from midjourney, animated with (undecided)


<br>img2vid: third-person clip of current activity/location/context
<br><br>For most contexts, DeepSeek R1 (8B) is the perfect LLM<br>
<br>huihui_ai's abliterated version is uncensored
<br>only 8-10gb vram requirement
<br>some inconsistencies in longer stories
<br>requiring some redundant clarification
<br>For high intelligence tasks, ChatGPT 4.5 is the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://lmarena.ai" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://lmarena.ai" target="_blank">current leader</a><br>
For high-speed and cheap high-context tasks, Gemini 2 is leading in 3rd place<br><br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IbRkwS_xRt8"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"></div></div></a>Joe Hisaishi's Studio Ghibli 25 Years ConcertPeak<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/studio-ghibli/images/1/1d/BudokanBD.png" draggable="false"><br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=OLAK5uy_kYA4Y6z4N2WjnjFl3LNMQCMELS4tiz6Og"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"></div></div></a>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt OSTPeak<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="https://i9.ytimg.com/s_p/OLAK5uy_kYA4Y6z4N2WjnjFl3LNMQCMELS4tiz6Og/mqdefault.jpg?sqp=CLzS_r4Gir7X7AMICO62tr0GEAE=&amp;rs=AOn4CLD8ERbqepH6qZUM9r3PM8FdvxF-zg&amp;v=1739430766&amp;days_since_epoch=20170" draggable="false"><br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL8fZemLM-gGfJ2001AJEY8S-_qlbKnj_s"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"></div></div></a>Genshin Impact OSTPeak<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/gensin-impact/images/3/39/The_Wind_and_The_Star_Traveler.png" draggable="false"><br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o77MzDQT1cg"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"></div></div></a>Hytale - Announcement TrailerGameplay and visuals<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/o77MzDQT1cg/maxresdefault.jpg" draggable="false"><br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m4nLSX3XYLA"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"></div></div></a>''And Ever'' by Galofuf | Geometry Dash 2.2Music and visuals<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/m4nLSX3XYLA/maxresdefault.jpg" draggable="false"><br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jiwuQ6UHMQg"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"></div></div></a>Orchestra: Adrian von Ziegler's celtic collectionMix<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Mn6Ef-Fa5gk/maxresdefault.jpg" draggable="false"><br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OIdx-_QFnYI"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"></div></div></a>✨ cottagecore radio 🎧 instrumental acoustic/folk music ✨Mix<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/OIdx-_QFnYI/maxresdefault.jpg" draggable="false"><br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nWG7RyF08Fw"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"></div></div></a>Harp: cottagecore video game/ghibli musicMix<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/nWG7RyF08Fw/maxresdefault.jpg" draggable="false"><br><a class="auto-card-link-card" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OSC3yUxm-9s&amp;list=PL4SomisbNGarQXBurMLGcWx5HV18822J_&amp;index=10"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"></div></div></a>Piano: daydreamMix<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail" src="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/OSC3yUxm-9s/maxresdefault.jpg" draggable="false"><br><br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/comfyui/comments/1798gj9/autogen_inside_comfyui_with_local_llms/" target="_blank">https://www.reddit.com/r/comfyui/comments/1798gj9/autogen_inside_comfyui_with_local_llms/</a><br>
<a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/LocalLLaMA/comments/1icta5y/why_do_people_like_ollama_more_than_lm_studio/" target="_blank">https://www.reddit.com/r/LocalLLaMA/comments/1icta5y/why_do_people_like_ollama_more_than_lm_studio/</a>]]></description><link>projects\eldoria.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Eldoria.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 07:02:36 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/studio-ghibli/images/1/1d/BudokanBD.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/studio-ghibli/images/1/1d/BudokanBD.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Praxis: Information Management]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The purpose of this system is to manage all different kinds of content on your phone and PCs, with a hyperfixation on efficiency/minimalism<br>
Uses versatile industry standards like Markdown and, tech-wise, mostly just basic file/text operations to maximize compatibility and efficiency<br>On Android: Syncthing (Settings &gt; Behavior &gt; Autostart), Automate (certain Flows like Share) and Edge Shortcuts (automatic) must run at startup<br><br>Quickpooling is capturing pics/vids/audio/ideas/links/files with minimal friction<br>
Everything pools into only one p2p-synced folder, no categorization<br>
<br>Should prevent having to routinely cycle thru all the diff services/destination when its time to categorize or, even worse, search for something specific
<br>I used Automate to "program" these systems on Android with Edge Shortcuts<br><br>A popup with multi-line input box, cancel and confirm buttons<br>
If cancel pressed, close popup<br>
If confirm, append '\n&lt;!--- YYYY-mm-dd HH:mm:ss --&gt;\n{input}' to QUICKPOOL.md<br>
<br>ex. {newline}&lt;!--- 2025-03-05 08:39:01 --&gt;{newline}{input}
<br>format {input} to escape (aka. insert \ symbols before) hashtags
<br>In Automate, its easy to implement everything except the input formatting on Android<br>
On Windows, I kitbashed a Tkinter Python popup script together with Claude<br><br>The clipboard/share function can hold many formats of data: image, text]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">index.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 05:36:41 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>